Yo, what is up guys? My name's Jason and
in this video I'm going to be explaining
exactly how this beast works. Okay, this
is an AI automation that basically re
does all my content research for me and
basically can predict what it is that I
will need to post and give me all the
insights and data that I need to make
informed decisions on what to post.
Right? This works great because we're
not guessing about what to post. we
actually can see for a fact, you know,
this is the data. This is what's
performing well in my niche and like
this is what I need to be focusing on,
right? For example, I have scraped a
couple people here.
I've scraped all of my reels so I can
see the entire transcript of my reels.
uh the entire script, the hook, a p like
a breakdown of the hook, the caption,
the views, the likes, the comments, and
the post date, right? So, we can see
things like what's the best time to
post, uh what are what's getting the
best comment engagement, right? Uh which
that is basically like conversion, like
what is converting the best. Um and
across the competitor data set, we can
see that as well, right? And this is
great because, you know, when we have a
sheet like this full of data, we can
just drop it into chat GBT and use that
to come up with content ideas and stuff
like that and learn more about our
audience and learn more about, you know,
what's working right now on social
media. Uh, not only do you get a full
entire sheet like this full of data, but
you also get a report like this every
single week.
Hold on. You get a report like this
every single week on autopilot,
right? That's the thing about this
automation is that it runs every Sunday
at 3:00 a.m. So, literally while you're
sleeping,
you are doing content research, scraping
all the data, and getting insights. And
then you get a report like this on
content showing you what are the top
competitor videos, how many views, who's
the creator, when was it posted, link to
view the original post, why it worked,
right? Blah blah blah. Winning patterns
across the data set, right? So across
the entire data set, what are we seeing
are the winning patterns here? How can
we use this in our own content? Right?
And then it gives you hook ideas where
it basically combines the competitor
data set with your own reels to come up
with new hooks for your your uh
Instagram, right?
Cool. So many things you can do with
this data. Not only do you get the
report, but you get the sheet, which
like I mentioned, you can drop that into
chatbt.
And guys, basically, this is basically
AI automating. And I hate I hate to use
this word. I hate to use this word, but
it's basically replacing
the job of content researchers, right?
Previously, you used to have to hire VAS
or you would have to research yourself
and, you know, you'd hire people and put
together to put together a report like
this, right? Um, look at how great this
report is. it honestly this is probably
going to be better higher quality than
what a VA or or a content researcher
would do right because
I you know I have personally crafted
this automation and I've been working on
this for the past
like five maybe like three or four
months right I've gone through like five
different versions if you saw the
original the first one that I
That was like
like the V1. All right, this [__] is
dialed now. Like it's actually dialed
in. Um not only can it transcribe the
reels like with, you know, like talking
head videos, but it can also do um
visual videos, right? So, like there's
no there's no script to this video, but
since we have Gemini with computer
vision, it's actually able to watch the
video and then give you um
you know the video like the the the shot
list, right, for visual videos because
not all videos are like talking head.
So, it can handle I I I set this up. I
literally scrolled through my entire
feed and tested this on every single
reel that I every single type of reel
that I could find to like get this
dialed to make sure that it was
absolutely accurate. Um, cool.
So uh before I get into like the kind of
walkth through and sort of tutorial
um
I want to talk about the limitations and
also the costs. Let's talk about the
costs first. Okay. So I have
meticulously
calculated the costs and I made sure to
double triple check. Okay,
so in total, this entire workflow
literally costs 90 to run. So if you're
running this, let's say four times a
month, like every week, right? Once
every week, it'll cost you $4.
$4 per month to run this entire AI
workflow. That pays for all the AI
agents. It pays for the Gemini like
video analysis. It pays for the
scraping.
$4
uh per month, right? 90 cents per run.
The Appify cost is going to be about 25
cents per run. But Appify actually gives
you $5 worth of free credits. So you
could actually run this time you could
you could run this entire workflow about
20 times before you ever even have to
pay for Appify. So if you if you run it
just four times a month, the Appify cost
you can actually forget about. That'll
be totally free actually. Um
yeah. Um okay. And
the Gemini cost will be 30 cents per
run. So it cost 30 cents to do to to do
30 transcribes, right? It's going to be
about 30 cents there. Open router cost
is going to be about 35 cents per run.
And that is paying for the AI tokens
that it's using during the hook analysis
and the the final report guy, the
content strategist that puts together
the report at the end. Um, and then
obviously, you know, if you will have to
do an N8N subscription, which that's
going to be tw $24 per month, but you
know, I use N8N for like I mean, you
should have any and any anyways like
yeah, you should be automating your
business anyways, right? If you guys, a
lot of you probably know Zapier or
Make.com, right? N8N is the most
powerful automation platform. way better
than Zapier.
I like it better than Make. All right.
And you ask around, ask around. Anyone
will tell you N8N is the most powerful
automation platform. Way better than
Zapier. Okay? If you're like a noob,
then sure, maybe continue using Zapier.
But anyways, I'm going off on a tangent.
Let's stay focused here. So, cost
breakdown. Literally, you know for a
fact it's going to be about 90 cents per
run. Okay? Give or take. Um, now let's
talk about the limitations, okay?
because I know I I spent a lot of time
hyping this thing up and it is indeed
very very hype, but I want to talk about
um you know what what it's good for and
what it's not good for. Okay, what it is
good for is data analysis, right? And
making
giving you a better content strategy
that is based on evidence and facts and
hard data, right? we're making we're
making decisions on what to post or how
to go viral based on the data or even
how to convert, right? Like how to
convert at least into comment CTAs,
right? When I look at like, okay, how
well is a post converting into actual
dollar sales amount? Typically, you want
to look at the comment engagement ratio
because a comment means that the lead is
raising their hand, right? more leads,
more money, right? So, you can pretty
much make datainformed decisions on what
what content you need to double down on,
what content your competitors are doing
that's working well for them, what
content you should do to go viral for
views, what content you should do for
conversions, right? All based on the
data. And I think it's also good for
giving you ideas and direction and
strategy. Okay, that's what it is really
all about is better strategy that is
based on the data. Okay, now what it's
not good at is if you decide to turn
your brain off and you think that just
because you just because you post with
these hooks that you're going to go
viral or you know the content's going to
perform well. Okay, that's not how this
works. This is not a replacement for
your brain and your creative thinking. I
guarantee you that like I could give
this report to an experienced creator
and they would know what to do with all
the insights and the strategy. Okay?
They'd more look at the insights and the
strategy here. But if you're just going
to if you're thinking that this is just
like an easy peasy way to just copy,
turn your brain off and not use creative
thinking and you think that you're going
to be successful with this, then maybe
this isn't for you, right? Because this
is more for highle creators who want to
who want to have a better content
strategy that is based on data. Okay,
cool. All right. So, with that out of
the way, with all of that out of the
way, I want to go into
every single node. I'm going to go into
every single node and show you exactly
how this thing works at every single
step so that you can build this for
yourself for completely free. Okay. Now,
if you want the template so that you can
just oneclick copy and paste this into
your N8N, you're going to have to pay
because I spent hours and months and
hours in the trenches developing and
building this thing. Obviously, I can't
just give you the template away for
free, okay? But uh so if you want that
template, just go if you want the
template for this, go down in the
description below, join my school
community, and once you join my school
community, it's going to look something
like this. All right, you're going to go
to the classroom, you're going to go to
content engine, or it might be something
else. You might just search just search
IG research
agent. Search that. Um, actually don't
search that because that might bring you
to the wrong like deprecated. Just go to
classroom, go to content engine. It's
going to be right here. IG research
agent V5. Okay. And in there you're
going to have the setup guide where I
literally have a 50-minute video walking
you through exactly how to set this up.
And you have the downloadable JSON
template, right? So that you can go into
NAN and then just oneclick copy and
paste this just like this. Import from
file. You click that template. Boom.
Okay. This is my intellectual property
that I spent hours and months
developing. So that's why I have to
charge for it. Okay. But in this video,
look, if you're on a budget, that's fine
because in this video, I'm going to show
you exactly how to set this up for free.
All right? you're just going to have to
follow step by step and you know it's
going to be might take you a little bit
longer.
Okay, so the first thing here is we have
a schedule trigger. Okay, this is set to
go off at 3:00 a.m. every Sunday. So I
basically just, you know, weeks one I
set it to go on Sunday. You can change,
you know, you can obviously adjust this,
but I just set it off to go every Sunday
at 3:00 a.m. This is going to run. It's
going to clear the previous week's data.
So, let me actually run this right now.
I'll I'll uh show you what's happening
as we walk through here.
Make sure it's linked to the right one.
Yeah. Okay. So,
if I execute this, this is basically
what's going to happen. Every Sunday at
3:00 a.m., it's going to clear the
previous week's data. So, as you can
see, it just cleared all of my reels. It
cleared all my reels. It's now going to
grab my username from inside of this
node.
Okay. So, you just paste in your
username here. You put in your username.
That's what it's going to scrape here in
the Appify step. In the app ampify step,
we are
running an actor and getting a data set.
Okay. And this is what the JSON body
looks like that we're sending over.
We're literally just telling it we want
20 reels. And this is the username that
we're scraping. And it's pulling that
from our this node right here.
Uh right. And then I mentioned it's this
note is just clearing it's clearing the
previous week's data. So I have it
linked to the my real sheet which has
these headers right here. Okay. And uh
just clearing the sheet. Okay. Then it
goes and scrapes my reels. You can see
that it successfully scraped all of my
reels. Okay. Then what we're doing
is we are
uh filtering
for
only posts in the past three months.
Right? So out of the 20 posts that it
scrape, it's basically just scraped the
20 most recent posts from my account.
Then we're going to filter out of those
20 posts. We want only the recent ones
that I have posted in the past three
months. So basically if the time stamp
is after you know three months ago from
now
we want to include it. have not discard
it. And also big big thing here the
video duration has to be less than 300
seconds which I believe is
divided by it's 5 minutes right we have
a five minute maximum on the video
otherwise
you might get lives like Instagram lives
that will come in through the data set
and then mess up the entire flow right
because Um,
yeah, if it's like a 30 minute live,
then obviously it's going to error out
at the Gemini node. Okay, so we
basically got our reel. We got our 20
most reels, 20 most recent reels. We're
we filtered for only our reels that we
posted in the past 3 months. As you can
see, I've posted 13 reels in the past
three months. Um, but you know, for you
that might be more, right? It might be
all 20. All 20 of them might be posted
in the past three months. Now, we're
going to sort them by views. So, we want
to take this field called video play
count, and we want to sort it
descending.
That's going to sort all these 13 items
by views descending. So, the highest
views first, lowest views first. Then,
we're limiting it to the top 15. What
that basically means is we're just
dropping.
Basically, all that means is we're just
dropping the the bottom five. We don't
want those in the data set, right? It's
we're just dropping the bottom five
least performing posts because we don't
really care about those. But in my case,
I didn't even have I only had 13 that
I've posted in the past three three
months. So, it's just going to take all
13. But the maximum amount of reels that
it's going to scrape from your account
will be basically your top 15 most
viewed posts in the past three months.
Next, what we're doing is we are sending
those videos to Gemini. Um, and we're
using Gemini 2.5 Flash.
I wonder if Gemini has a is there a
Gemini is there a Gemini 3 flash now?
Because Gemini 3 Pro just came out.
Ah, okay. Gemini 3 Pro is available.
Gemini 3 Pro at the time of at the time
of this recording, Gemini 3 Pro
literally like just uh just released
like 10 hours ago. But uh
in the Yeah. Anyways, we're using 2.5
Flash here. Okay. To transcribe and use
computer vision to watch the video and
get a
um
a script. Here is the prompt. Okay. So,
if you want, you can screenshot this and
then basically like
here's what I would do. If if you wanted
to set this up for free, just screenshot
like you're on the YouTube video right
now, right? Just screenshot it and then
show in Finder and then open it up. And
now you can actually copy just like
that. Right? That's how I would copy
this prompt for free.
Okay.
But uh let me just scroll through. So
this is the entire prompt. We're
basically just saying, "Hey, you're a
social media content analysis analyst.
You want to watch this video and extract
a raw breakdown." So, first we want to
identify the video format. Like, is this
a visual video? Is this a meme video?
All right? Otherwise, it's just going to
be a a script video. So, for the visual
videos, here's how you should give us
the script. For script driven videos,
uh, for script driven videos,
this is how you should give us the
script. Just transcribe it. For visual
montage videos, this is how you should
give us the script. For meme or comedy
format videos, this is how you should
give us the script,
right? And then it has instructions in
here about distinguishing between the
actual content and the background audio.
Right.
And then it has some output constraints.
Okay. So that's really all that's
happening in the Gemini node is we're
just and we're sending that video URL
that we scraped from
Instagram. If we open this up, this is
basically just like the uh
it's like the download URL for the
video. That's what we're sending over to
Gemini. And then it's using that video
URL to download it and then watch it
with this prompt.
So, we can see that it just got done
analyzing all 13 of my reels. And then
the next step after that is it's passing
it off to this hook analyzer agent. And
inside of here, we are using Claude XML
format for the prompt because Claude
likes that. It's like a good way to
structure the prompt. Um, and yeah, this
is the prompt here. Basically, we're
saying, hey, identify the real hook of
the video. You know, here's how to
identify the hook. You have, is there
text overlay at the start? That's
usually it. If it's a visual video, like
a split screen or like a before after,
the structure of the video is actually
the hook because it's like a visual
video. Is there someone talking with no
text or structure? In that case, the
opening statement is usually the hook.
Um, ignore background music, ignore
generic audio, blah blah blah. And then
we have examples. examples really really
help with Claude to
understand like the type of output that
you're looking for. Right.
So, uh
yeah. Oh, let me um
scroll through this. If you want to copy
the prompt,
boom.
Okay. You can copy the entire prompt for
free. Maybe I can just
Oh, there we go. Maybe I can just show
you the entire.
Uh, I feel like that's too small though.
Whatever.
There.
There is the entire prompt.
Okay,
that's the prompt for the hook analyzer.
Maybe I'll even include
may maybe I'll even include the prompts
for free down below.
Anyways, okay. No, honestly though, it's
like dude, I spent so long like co like
writing these prompts. Like I literally
spent like hours and hours like
fine-tuning these prompts. I really
don't think I can give these away for
free. Okay, anyways.
Then it's just putting all the reels in
our sheet. Okay, so as you can see, it
just got done. Boom. Transcribed all of
our reels, all 13 of them, and then put
them in the sheet with the views, the
likes, the comments, blah blah blah. And
we can see that this is all pretty
accurate. 321,000 views, 14K or like
about 15K likes, 14.9K, 6.7K.
Yeah, very, very accurate.
Cool.
And now what it's doing Oh, let me show
this right so you already saw the prompt
there
and then for the model here I'm using
open router and I'm using claude haiku
4.5 as the model because I did a lot of
research and it's the best model for
this task we do we need it to be like a
little smart enough to know and identify
hooks but not so smart that it's going
to be like expensive like claude sonnet
is pretty expensive. So, Haiku was a
nice like middle ground. If you want the
highest quality, you can definitely bump
the model up to Sonnet 4.5. And I have
noticed that that does actually improve
the accuracy of like identifying what
the actual hook of the video is. Um,
you know, you can also mess around with
the prompt, but yeah, that's basically I
chose Haiku 4.5 for the model there. And
then the next step is that it's
basically
you know getting the document the sheet
and then it's sending over
we're grabbing the we're grabbing the
thumbnail like the display URL and
mapping that in. We're grabbing the real
URL. We are grabbing the username and
then we are grabbing the transcript. Big
thing here is that I like to slice off
the transcript at 10,000 characters. The
Google Sheets cell limit is 50,000
characters.
But you know in a in I just want to
account for any edge cases, any weird
cases where
sometimes maybe I don't know if the
Gemini node gets stuck in a loop and it
just keeps on transcribing and it's like
a 100,000 character transcript,
you're going to get an error if you try
to stuff that into a sheet node, right?
I also put this fallback. This is
actually the most the more important
thing is that in here when I feed it in
the transcript right to to show it like
hey this is the transcript extract the
hook. We got to have this fall back
here. Uh, basically this is saying like,
okay, if the Gemini node failed, which
sometimes it does just randomly, there's
nothing you can really do about that,
but like one out of every, I don't know,
30 will fail for some reason. In that
case, you want to account for that
error, right? Just in case it fails,
we're just going to give this message,
right? Okay. And then the workflow
continues and we can continue on without
it without it stopping the entire
workflow and throwing us an error.
Right? So that's another key important
thing that we're doing right here
is we're setting that error handling
logic. Basically if we if the transcript
failed, we're just going to give this
little message right here that just says
transcript failed. That way the workflow
can continue without it stopping the
entire thing and then you having to run
it all over again. Blah blah blah. Okay.
So yeah, basically pretty simple stuff
here though. We're just mapping in all
of the we're mapping in the transcript.
We're mapping in the hook analysis that
we got from the hook analyzer step. We
are mapping in the caption, the views,
the likes, the comments, and the post
date. And that's all that's happening in
the append rows. Google sheet step. Then
the next step after that is to clear out
the competitor reels sheet. So, you
can't see, but it just um it just
cleared out the sheet and Oh.
Uhoh.
Why don't I just try and
Oh, it just loaded as I left.
Let me go back to the sheet.
Oh, what's wrong with my Wi-Fi? Why is
it so slow?
Dang.
[clears throat] Ah, I don't know what
was going on there. My Wi-Fi just kind
of pooped out for a second. Anyways,
where was I?
So,
right. Okay. So, now what it's doing is
we're moving on to phase two. So, we
already scraped all of my reels. As you
can see, we scraped all my reels. All
the transcripts were successful. So
yeah, no problems there. And what do we
want to do now is move on to scraping
our competitors. Okay. So it's going to
basically well the first step is it's
going to clear the competitor uh reels
from last week, right? So these all
clear out and we get new fresh data,
right? And that's important because
we're basically you're going to get a
different report every week with the
latest and greatest reels, right? This
is grabbing reels from only the past two
weeks, right? So, as you go on week by
week, you'll get new reels of
Oh, that was that's what was going on.
Yeah, I think Google Sheets had a
problem there for a second. For sure.
For sure. That was a Google Sheets like
weird little thing that was happening
there. That's okay, though, because that
actually gives us a chance to show you
what's going on with the um thing. So,
let's pin this and we can start it from
the uh this start. Okay. So, we don't we
did all of our reels. Now, what's going
to happen next is it's going to clear
our our competitor reels and then it's
going to get our competitors and start
scraping them. So, if we go Oops. If we
go here, we can watch it happen. I click
execute.
Oops. See, boom. It just cleared
everything out, right? Cleared out the
previous week's data. And that's, you
know, same thing here. It's just
grabbing our sheet from the list.
Competitor reals clear whole sheet keep
first row. And then the next step is
it's grabbing our competitors from our
competitor list sheet. Right.
And that's going to be right here.
[clears throat]
So, um,
yeah,
it basically just it'll grab like if you
put if you put like 20 competitors in
the list, you can do that. It's just
only going to take the first five. So,
whatever whoever is highlighted, it's
only going to scrape them. You can
scrape up to five, right? But if you
only put three people in here, then
it'll only do three. Okay. So, um, yeah.
So, I usually, you know, you can do
three, you could do five, whatever.
Don't really matter. But, uh, cool. So,
then it's grabbing the it's grabbing
basically all of their profile URLs and
then it's sending, right? It's limiting
them to only the top five, right? So,
boom. And then uh limit to the five
first items, right? So, that even if you
have like 20 people in here, it'll just
only do the first five. again, sending
over the scrape. Sending it over to the
scraper. It's the Instagram real
scraper. It's going to be this guy on
Ampify. Here's the URL right here. Um,
yeah. So, it's going to be that. This is
the scraper. And then we're just sending
over this JSON body that is uh we're
we're grabbing the the the latest 15
reels from each of our competitors and
then we're mapping in their username
from,
you know, the previous node, right?
Where we go we're we're basically
mapping in all the guy the people in the
list that we just got.
So it's going to loop over every single
competitor. As you can see, it's going
over the first one right now. And I
believe this one is probably ROR. Yeah.
So it's going over ROR right now.
Uh
and
in this step again we want to make sure
that we are filtering. Okay. So the time
stamp of the post has to be after two
weeks ago, right? And also again we want
to filter out all those lives and and
super long videos, right? If it's over
five minutes, we want to discard it,
right? We do not want that. Um, okay.
Boom. And and so now what we're doing
here is we're basically the exact same
process that we did for our reels. We're
just doing that five times, right? For
each of our competitors. It's the exact
same process. We're just doing it. We're
just looping five times over each
competitor, right? So we just did ROR.
And now if we see if we check our sheet.
Oh, okay. This one failed. See, that's
good though because otherwise it would
have just crashed the entire workflow,
you know, and this is like really it's,
you know, there's nothing you can do
about this, you know, it's you're going
to get some of these sometimes. Trust
me, dude. Well, actually, there is
something that you can do about it. I
look, I figured out how to make it
absolutely bulletproof and make sure
that that we get the transcription every
time, but
it's too complicated for the setup.
and and like it it's just too
complicated and I I figured that it
would just add a lot more complexity to
the setup and I didn't want to make it I
just wanted this to be simple and for it
to work right. So,
but basically if you do want if you
wanted to make it absolutely
bulletproof, you kind of have to do a
Cloudflare worker setup to access the
Instagram download link because
Instagram is funky about how they how
how how it lets you access their link.
It's an IPv4 versus IPv6 issue. Anyways,
okay, cool.
So,
um, you know, we still get the caption
though, so we still like know what the
video is about.
Um, all right, cool. So, now it's going
over the second competitor.
I already covered this node. Um, again,
yeah, we're filtering for now minus two
weeks ago.
And oh, this is another error handle. So
sometimes,
you know, you'll sometimes you'll put a
competitor in the list, but they haven't
posted anything in the past two weeks.
And so this filter will come back empty,
right? And that would break the
workflow. But we have this if node in
here to basically say
it's basically checking if it's empty,
right? If if if they haven't posted
anything in the past two weeks, then
we're just going to skip over them and
we're just going to move on to the next
person. That's all that this is doing,
right?
Cool. And that's just like this right
here. Again, we're sorting by video play
count descending so we can sort by
views, highest to lowest. And then we
only want the top five highest viewed
videos in the past two weeks from each
of our competitors.
And then
um in this node
again, same Gemini
node, right? Uh yeah, I already showed
this prompt. I'll go over it again
maybe.
Okay, let me scroll slowly through it.
Cool. There you go.
So, same prompt there, same everything
there. It's like the exact same node as
this one. And then again, we have the
hook analyzer again. Same exact node
pretty much. Yeah, same exact node as
the one on top. Here is the prompt. I
will scroll through it slowly again.
Okay.
And then um
same thing here. We're just adding the
row. We're just adding them to the
sheet.
Yeah, just like that.
And as you can see, they're getting
added in. And as you can see, the the
transcription is pretty reliable. You
know, it only failed on only failed on
one.
Um,
cool.
So, it's gone over the third person. It
has two more to go. While we're waiting
for this, um,
you might be wondering like, okay, how
do I copy the Google Sheet template for
free, right? Well,
well, actually,
if you're smart, you could probably get
it from this video, but uh
no, because this is private. Okay, good.
[laughter] So, you can't get it from
this video. Yeah, I was afraid I exposed
the link, but this is private. So, even
if you go try and access this link,
it'll be Yeah, you'll need to sign in.
It'll be private.
But here's how you copy the Google sheet
template. Okay, if you want to do it for
free, look, you literally just need to
make a Google sheet like this. Okay,
just copy the the format here. You need
the thumbnail, URL, username,
transcript, hook, analysis, caption,
views, likes, comments, posted. It'll
take like two seconds, right? You just
need to copy the format of these sheets
with all three sheets and then, you
know, you can then link them. You'll
need to, you know, select the right
sheet and link or you, you know, select
the correct document and link the right
sheet.
All right, it's on the fourth person
now. So, I'm just going to pause and
then come back when it's done.
Okay. Oh, sorry. Nope. Just got done
with the fourth person. So, we still got
to wait. It's going to do that fifth
person now.
Okay. All right. So, it just got done
putting in all the data for all five
competitors. And as you can see, it did
a splendid job. Okay. And now we what we
can do is we can actually sort these by
views. So, if we want to see highest to
lowest views, we can see that. We can
also sort by comments, which I like to
see. If we want to see highest comments
to lowest comments, we can see kind of,
you know, the that's more focused on
like conversion, right? But, uh, cool.
So, yeah, we'll just do uh, you know, we
can sort by views. Look, we can look at
highest viewed to lowest viewed in our
competitor data set.
Very nice. Okay. Okay. And now what it's
doing is
it's sorting views again because our
competitors went in, you know, one at a
time. Basically, one at a time. So, we
need to resort them. That's basically
doing what I just did here, right? It
sorting views highest to lowest. It's
just doing that automated, right? Simple
views descending.
And then we're setting the data here.
We're setting the data into strings that
we can easily map into our content
strategist agent. So basically just all
of our competitor reals data, we're just
making that into a string that we can
then feed into our agent. And same thing
with our reals data. We're just taking
every single like literally all of the
data in the sheet and then just um
turning it into a string. And it's in
JSON format. So, it's parsible like it's
readable for the it's all organized,
right? It's organized into text that is
good for an LLM to be able to organize
and see and read through.
So,
now it's thinking for a really long time
because this is our strategist guy.
We're using we're using Claude Sonnet
4.5 to do this step.
And um
here's the prompt here. We're basically
telling it, okay, here's our username.
Here's my reels. We're feeding in the
entire data set for my reels. And then
we're feeding in the entire data set for
competitor reels. Again, we're using XML
format because Claude likes its prompts
in XML format.
And yeah, it's basically just going to
go over the all of the data. And then
here's what we're saying. We're saying
you're an expert Instagram content
strategist. Um, step one, select the top
five competitor videos. Take the first
five reels. They're already sorted by
views. Extract the data. Analyze each
top five video. For each of them, you
want to figure out what's the hook, URL,
views, post date, username. You want to
figure out the psychological trigger at
play, the execution mechanics, what most
people would miss about why this worked.
Then we want to identify winning
patterns. So we want to identify we want
to analyze both of the data sets
together. We want to look at all the
patterns across all the competitor reels
and we want to cross reference that with
um top performing we want to cross
reference that with our top performing
content, right?
And then we want to find patterns that
work in the market and fit our style and
our audience, right? And again this is
variable, right? So whatever username
you put in, it will put that into the
prompt. Right? For each of those
patterns, we want the framework, we want
the underlying psychology, when it
doesn't work, why it would work for us
specifically, and we want to create 10
hook ideas. We want to blend insights
from both of the data sets. We want to
use competitor frameworks like what's
working in the market. We want to adapt
it to Jason's authentic voice and style.
Each hook needs an explanation of why it
works. And then finally, step five, we
want to do a key takeaway. So we want to
synthesize in insights from both data
sets. And we want the single most
important strategic insight like what
are the competitors doing successfully?
What's working for us and our audience?
What's the gap between them, the
opportunity? And then we have some more
instructions about like look, you're
creative, you're charismatic, you need
to think outside the box. Weak insights
equal wasted money. find the hidden
patterns and psychological mechanisms
that explain why content goes viral.
And then we have some more instructions
about the required depth. And then we
just have
we specify the the [sighs] JSON format
that we want back. So we want we need a
structured JSON output from this step so
that we can later map that into the
report that we're going to get. Critical
JSON requirements. This is just output
formatting.
It's just output formatting here. And
then we have a writing checklist. Cool.
And then for here, one key thing here is
obviously you want to select the model
cloud sonic 4.5, but you also want to
make sure you add an option for response
format. And that's got to be JSON,
right? That way we get
a that way we get an output like this
where it's a structured output instead
of just giving us a text otherwise it's
just going to respond in plain text
right which we can't we can't create a
report out of that. So boom it did that.
this code node step is oh gosh
yeah yeah I don't know how you're going
to be able to copy this for free I mean
I'll go over it it's just going to be
painstakingly m like
anyways this code node basically just
converts it into a
just slowly go over
This code node is basically just
converting our clawed response, our AI
response into a nicely formatted HTML
document
that we can then send as an email. And
this is all the code for that.
Boom. Okay.
[sighs] All right.
So, that's what it's doing there. It's
basically just formatting a nicely
formatted HTML email. And then finally,
we are sending off that report. Now, I
have it set to send it to me. But if
you're running this for a client, then
all you'd need to do is just, you know,
change the username and change the email
to the client's email. And then you'd
obviously need to duplicate another
sheet for them, right? And then relink
it to their sheet, right? But once this
is set up, it runs every Sunday. You
don't need to do anything, right? Like
it'll run every Sunday on autopilot. And
you'll basically have like if you're a
content agency, you'll basically have
like automated fulfillment, right? Not
completely, but you'll have automated
content research and reports for your
clients.
Pretty dope. And it only costs you 90
cents per run. So, let's take a look at
what that hopefully I showed everything
here. Yeah,
let's take a look at that email report
that we got. Boom.
Instagram research report. We have top
competitor videos. First one is by Mino.
surprising my girlfriend. Then we have,
did you know you can change the angle by
Roar Keith?
Then we have Most people don't realize
there's one thing you got to do if you
want to survive on social media.
Nice from RPN. Very, very cool. Then we
have How to Edit Your Photo Angles again
by Roar Keith.
Oh, that was actually the same.
Wait.
Ah, okay. It had a little trouble on
this one because uh the transcription
failed on this one.
So, it didn't uh know what to do there.
But, normally that won't be a problem.
Um,
how much money I made as a creator each
year. Nice.
6.7K. 1.5K like or 253. Let's check and
make sure the view count is accurate.
Yep. Nice.
Sweet.
Yeah.
Yeah, it did a good job. But the only
one it kind of messed up on here was uh
here. That's just because the
transcription failed. But it really like
most of the time you it won't work. That
won't happen. And like I said like to
fix the way to fix that issue is so
complicated that's really not worth the
effort, right? You're getting like
90% of the results that you need. Any
extra on top is really not going to make
a difference, right? So cool.
Impossible made trivial pattern. So it
has winning patterns for my competitors
earned vulnerability story arc.
This pattern structure's content is a
personal journey where the creator
shares both struggles and wins. But
crucially the vulnerability comes after
establishing credibility through
results. I think this is probably
Mino's. Yeah. Mino Lee's $20 to 575K
progression works because the struggle
is so relatable. It disarms skepticism.
The growth trajectory proves the method
works at scale. Right. For Jason
Cooperson, this is untapped gold. his
journey from college essays with chat
GBT to running 50K plus automation
business. Wow, that is scary accurate.
I don't even know how it got this and
probably because I talked about it in
one of my reels. Wow. His vulnerability
talks about feeling lonely at 160k
followers shows he has raw material. It
just needs to be woven into a
progression story.
Wow.
Okay. Um, cool.
Meta proof demonstration. This advanced
pattern uses the content itself as proof
of the thesis. Self-referential. Yeah,
this is a common theme with like
content, you know, marketing creators
like artist story. The human narrative
matters through beautifully shot human
story. Oh, the RPN cabin video
demonstrating the human narrative
matters.
or the fake artist story that
manipulates emotion to prove stories
matter more than art.
Show don't tell.
Cool. I replace my entire Okay. And
these are the hook ideas that it is
saying would work for my account. I
replaced my entire content team with
three automations that run while I
sleep. And they're cons they're more
consistent than I ever was. Nice. Most
automation tutorials lie to you. Here's
what they don't show. So, the six hours
of errors before the 20-minute result,
right? Earned vulnerability pattern.
It's using that earned vulnerability
pattern to disrupt oversimplified
automation content flooding the market.
Nice. Positioning me as the trutht
teller who respects viewers
intelligence.
Nice. Acknowledging the messy reality
upfront.
I let my 13-year-old cousin use my 3K
automation. He built a client onboarding
system. That's cool. Okay. Kind of
interesting hook there. That's cool.
This weaponizes the if a 13-year-old can
do it. Okay, cool. Instagram algorithm
changed. Here's what 3 billion views
taught me about the new rules everyone's
getting wrong. I analyzed 100 reels in
the blank space. The top performers this
adapts his fitness and niche analysis
video to structure any vertical. Yeah,
that's very accurate. I was planning on
doing that anyways. data driven pattern
find positioning me as the data driven
pattern finder who does the research so
viewers don't have to
nice
analyzed 100 reels in the niche space
the top performers all use this one
pattern yeah great your content isn't
bad your distribution system is here's a
seven platform auto poster that 7x my
output overnight nice I built an AI that
stalks my competitors and writes my
content strategy every Sunday I haven't
manually researched in four months.
Nice. Everyone's talking about chatbt
for content. I'm using it to run my
business operations.
Nice.
All right. And this one positions me as
operating at a more sophisticated level
than the content creator masses who just
use AI for captions and thumbnails.
Very cool.
I spent $3,000. I tested every AI video
tool this month. Here's the only three
that are worth your time. And yeah, I
would probably cut this, but these this
is good hook. Creator who's beating me
on views doesn't have better ideas. They
have a better system. I stole it. Here's
how it works. Yo, that's dope. I like
that. These are all like such good
ideas, right? And like I said, this is
good for like insights, right? It's good
for insights and it's good for
crafting a better content strategy. This
is not meant to replace your creativity,
though. The only thing that this really
replaces is content research and
strategy based on data and data. That's
what it really is. It's replacing
content research, right? Manually going
out and researching and transcribing
reels and it's replacing data analysis,
right? We're replacing data analysis and
content re and and research because
those are low-level tasks that are just
pretty straightforward, right?
Now that we're getting the analysis and
now that we're getting the insights,
what we have to do here is use our own
creativeness to take these insights and
turn it into viral content. Right?
Um, key takeaway. The strategic gap
between Jason's content and top
performer is distribution of
vulnerability and narrative structure.
Competitors like Mino weave personal
journey and struggle into nearly every
video. Creating parasocial connection
makes technical content feel like
following a friend's success story
rather than consuming tutorials from an
expert. Ooh, that's great. That's great.
Jason Cooperson has the raw material,
his JBT College essays, origin 160k
monthlong breaks, revenue transparency,
but it exists in isolated vulnerability
post rather than being woven into his
automation tutorials as proof that
systems exist to solve creator burnout
and overwhelm.
Nice. Highest ROI shift is treating
every automation tutorial not as a
feature demo but a chapter in the larger
like story.
Cool. Now you'll get a different report
based on your competitor list. So if you
like you'll get a completely different
report based on the list of people that
you're putting in here, right? because
it heavily bases the report based on top
performing content in this competitor
data set. So, if I was to include
another person in the report like this
guy, Junior, who's also great,
um it would have some very different
ideas for me because a lot of his like
he if I included him in the list, then
his reels would would dominate a lot of
the top performers and therefore it
would base our strategy more on that,
All right. So, yeah.
Um,
okay. All right. Cool. So, yeah, that is
the entire automation from start to
finish exactly how it works. And again,
guys, if you would like to just copy
this oneclick, copy and paste, I have it
in my school community. You can go down
in the description below and click that
link to join my school community. Once
you get in here, uh, we have a really
dope community of a lot of cool
creators, content creators who are doing
crazy things. And I'm in there every
day. We got group calls, group calls
every day. Uh, or so, not every day, but
twice a week, I hop on with the gang and
we all vibe out. I help you guys, right,
with uh content strategy and how to use
AI, how to stay on top of it, how to not
get left behind, how to go viral and,
you know, convert more and make more
money from your content with these
advanced AI strategies so you can work
faster, smarter, and actually how to how
to use AI to enhance your creative
abilities, right? And enhance your
content strategy. That's what this group
is all about. And like I said, if you,
you know, if you want the template, it's
right here in the school community. I
have a full setup guide that shows you
exactly step by step how to get it
running. Uh, it's really easy peasy, not
too crazy. And and like I said, the
Google Sheets template is in here as
well as the JSON file so that you can
oneclick copy and paste this workflow.
And that way you don't have to, you
know, like I showed before, all you need
to do is um click create workflow and
import from file and then just import
that template that I have in my school
community and it will load in
automatically.
So
cool. Yeah. And aside from that, there's
a ton of other sauce in here. I have an
entire resource library full of like a
ton of other automations, some other
strategies, and then I have more content
strategy stuff here, highle content
strategy. We have some Slack
automations, finance automations. We
have NAN basics. So, even if you're a
beginner to NADN, I got you covered. I
have like very basic stuff to go over.
Um, and yeah, that's pretty much it.
Shameless self-plug.
So guys, I hope you enjoyed the video. I
hope you found this valuable. I will
catch you guys in the next one. Peace
out.